# Chenkai Weng

+1-224-307-3331 | ckweng@u.northwestern.edu | ckweng.github.io

#### RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research interest lies in cryptography, with a focus on secure multi-party computation and zero-knowledge proofs. I have participated in projects related to the security of garbled circuits protocol, efficient generation of correlated oblivious transfer, private data analysis in healthcare systems and scalable interactive zero-knowledge proofs.

#### EDUCATION

Northwestern University

Evanston, IL

PhD in Computer Science; Advisor: Xiao Wang

Sept. 2019 - Present

Xidian University

Xi'an, China

BSc in Information Security

Sept. 2015 - June 2019

#### EXPERIENCE

Research Assistant

Evanston, IL

Northwestern University

Sept. 2020 - Present

- Scalable and Efficient interactive zero-knowledge protocols based on VOLE.
- Correlated oblivious transfer based on VOLE.
- Concrete security of the garbled circuit protocol.
- Design, implementation and evaluation of MPC/ZK applications.

## AI Research Summer Associate

New York, NY

JPMorgan Chase

Jun. 2022 - Sept. 2022

• Cryptographic research.

Research Intern

Remote

Microsoft Research

May. 2021 - Jul. 2021

 Design and Develop secure multi-party computation and differential privacy applications for online conversion measurement.

Teaching Assistant

Evanston, IL

Northwestern University

Sept. 2020 - Dec. 2020

• Introduction to Cryptography

### Security Engineering Intern

Beijing, China

Alibaba Group

July 2018 - Jan. 2019

- Survey on secure multi-party computation techniques.
- Implementation of threshold encryption and digital signature schemes based on MPC.
- Implementation of private set intersection protocol and order-preserving encryption schemes.

## **Publications**

#### 1. AntMan: Interactive Zero-Knowledge Proofs with Sublinear Communication

Chenkai Weng, Kang Yang, Zhaomin Yang, Xiang Xie, and Xiao Wang ACM Conference on Computer and Communications Security (CCS), 2022

## 2. More Efficient Secure Matrix Multiplication for Unbalanced Recommender Systems

Zhicong Huang, Cheng Hong, Wen-jie Lu, Chenkai Weng, Hunter Qu IEEE Transactions on Dependable and Secure Computing (TDSC)

#### 3. Constant-Overhead Zero-Knowledge for RAM Programs

Nicholas Franzese, Jonathan Katz, Steve Lu, Rafail Ostrovsky, Xiao Wang, Chenkai Weng ACM Conference on Computer and Communications Security (CCS), 2021

#### 4. Efficient Conversions for Zero-Knowledge Proofs with Applications to Machine Learning

Chenkai Weng, Kang Yang, Xiang Xie, Jonathan Katz, Xiao Wang USENIX Security Symposium, 2021

#### 5. Efficient and Affordable Zero-Knowledge Proofs for Circuits and Polynomials over Any Field

Kang Yang, Pratik Sarkar, Chenkai Weng, Xiao Wang ACM Conference on Computer and Communications Security (CCS), 2021

## 6. Fast, Scalable, and Communication-Efficient Zero-Knowledge Proofs for Boolean and Arithmetic Circuits Chenkai Weng, Kang Yang, Jonathan Katz, Xiao Wang

IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy (Oakland), 2021

## 7. Developing High Performance Secure Multi-Party Computation Protocols in Healthcare: A Case Study of Patient Risk Stratification

Xiao Dong, David Randolph, Chenkai Weng, Abel Kho, Jennie Rogers, Xiao Wang AMIA Informatics Summit, 2021

#### 8. Ferret: Fast Extension for coRRElated oT with small communication

Kang Yang, Chenkai Weng, Xiao Lan, Jiang Zhang, Xiao Wang ACM Conference on Computer and Communications Security (CCS), 2020

## 9. Better Concrete Security for Half-Gates Garbling (in the Multi-Instance Setting)

Chun Guo, Jonathan Katz, Xiao Wang, Chenkai Weng, Yu Yu International Cryptology Conference (CRYPTO), 2020

#### TALKS

- Aug. 2021 "Efficient Conversions for Zero-Knowledge Proofs with Applications to Machine Learning", USENIX Security Symposium, 2021.
- 2. May. 2021 "Wolverine: Fast, Scalable, and Communication-Efficient Zero-Knowledge Proofs for Boolean and Arithmetic Circuits", IEEE Security & privacy (Oakland), 2021.
- 3. Mar. 2021 "Fast, Scalable, and Communication-Efficient Zero-Knowledge Proofs", Security and privacy seminar at Duke University.
- Nov. 2020 "Ferret: Fast Extension for coRRElated oT with small communication", ACM Conference on Computer and Communications Security (CCS), 2020.
- Aug. 2020 "Better Concrete Security for Half-Gates Garbling (in the Multi-Instance Setting)", International Cryptology Conference (CRYPTO), 2020.

#### Software

## EMP library

- 1. [EMP-TOOL] Float-point arithmetic based on Boolean circuits. Cryptographic building blocks.
- 2. [EMP-OT] Correlated-OT based on VOLE (The Ferret protocol).
- 3. [EMP-ZK] Interactive zero-knowledge proof protocols. For the circuit model, it supports boolean and arithmetic circuits, and their conversions. It also supports proving degree-2 polynomial satisfiabilies.